# Hyung-Kwon Ko

College of Computing KAIST, Daejeon hyungkwonko@gmail.com https://hyungkwonko.info

#### About

Hyung-Kwon Ko is a researcher at KAIST Interaction Lab. His main research areas include Human-Computer Interaction, Human-Centered AI, and Information Visualization. He designs, prototypes, and evaluates interactive systems to innovate people's working paradigms based on a thorough investigation of their need. Experienced in AI models from both academia and industry, he is currently interested in how foundation models (e.g., DALL-E) could help people in visual art domains perform creative works.

## Education

2019 – 2021	<b>Seoul National University</b> , Seoul, Korea Master of Science in Computer Science and Engineering (Advisor: Dr. Jinwook Seo)
2014 – 2019	Hanyang University, Seoul, Korea Bachelor of Science in Mathematics, Minor in Industrial Engineering

## **Publications**

## Conference & Journal Papers

- [b6] Ko, H.-K., Park, G., Jeon, H., Jo, J., Kim, J., Seo, J. (2023).

  Large-scale Text-to-Image Generation Models for Visual Artists' Creative Works.

  Proceedings of the International Conference on Intelligent User Interfaces (IUI '23), 1-15.
- [a5] Ko, H.-K.\*, An, S.\*, Park, G., Kim, S.K., Kim, D., Kim, B., Seo, J. (2022).
  We-toon: A Communication Support System between Writers and Artists in Collaborative Webtoon Sketch Revision.
  Proceedings of the ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology (UIST '22), 1-14.
- [a4] Jeon, H.\*, Ko, H.-K.\*, Lee, S., Jo, J., Seo, J. (2022).

  Uniform Manifold Approximation with Two-phase Optimization.

  Proceedings of IEEE Conference on Visualization and Visual Analytics (VIS '22), 80-84.
- [a3] Jeon, H., Ko, H.-K., Jo, J., Kim, Y., Seo, J. (2021).
   Measuring and Explaining the Inter-Cluster Reliability of Multidimensional Projections.
   IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics (In Proceedings of VIS '21), 28(1):551-561.
- [a2] Jung, S., Choe, K., Park, S., Ko, H.-K., Seo, J. (2021).
   Mixed-Initiative Approach to Extract Data from Pictures of Medical Invoice.
   IEEE Pacific Visualization Symposium (PacificVis '21), 111-115.
- [a1] Ko, H.-K., Jo, J., Seo, J. (2020).

  Progressive Uniform Manifold Approximation and Projection.

  EG/VGTC Conference on Visualization (EuroVis '20), 133-137.

## Preprints & Publications in Progress

- [b5] Ko, H.-K., Son, K., Jin, H., Choi, Y., Kim, J. (2023).

  Crowdiffusion: Text Prompting of Large-scale Text-to-Image Generation Models by Example.

  (In Progress)
- [b4] Shin, H., Lee, Y., Ko, H.-K., Kim, J. (2023).

  Enabling Prototyping of AI-infused UIs with Task-level Specifications.

  (In Progress)

1/3

[b3] Yun, S., Jeon, H., Ko, H.-K., Seo, J. (2023).

Scalable Readability Evaluation of Graph Layouts on Distributed Environments.

(In Progress)

[b2] Choi, J.\*, Song, J.\*, Jeon, H., Kim, Y., Ko, H.-K., Seo, J. (2022).

How Disentanglement Affects Users' Interpretation, Control, and Sentiment when Using Generative

**Models**. (Under Review)

[b1] Jeon, H., Aupetit, M., Lee, S., Ko, H.-K., Kim, Y., Seo, J. (2022).

Distortion-Aware Brushing for Interactive Cluster Analysis in Multidimensional Projections.

Arxiv Preprint (Under Review)

## **Experience**

06/2022 – Present	KAIST Interaction Lab (KIXLAB), Daejeon, Korea
-------------------	--

Researcher (Advisor: Dr. Juho Kim)

10/2021 – 06/2022 Naver Webtoon Corp., Seongnam, Korea

AI Research Scientist, Webtoon AI

04/2021 – 09/2021 Naver Webtoon Corp., Seongnam, Korea

AI Research Intern, Webtoon AI

03/2019 – 08/2019 Human-Computer Interaction Lab, Seoul, Korea

Research Intern (Advisor: Dr. Jinwook Seo)

01/2019 – 02/2019 **LG Electronics Inc.**, Seoul, Korea

Research Intern, CTO Division

06/2018 – 08/2018 **Wesleyquest Inc.**, Seoul, Korea

Research Associate

## **Honors and Awards**

2022	Gary Marsden Travel Award (Full travel support for UIST '22: \$2,800 USD), ACM SIGCHI
2018	Big Data Contest (3 <sup>rd</sup> Place, Prize Money: \$900 USD), NIA and Korea Big Data Forum
2018	AI Novel Writing Competition (2 <sup>nd</sup> Place, Prize Money: \$18,000 USD), KT Corporation and
	KOCCA
2017	Academic Research Competition (2nd Place, Prize Money: \$180 USD), Hanyang University
2014 - 2018	Merit-based Scholarship (6 semesters), Hanyang University

## **Invited Talks and Seminars**

1. Large-scale Text-to-Image Generation Models for Visual Artists' Creative Works *Shandong University, Qingdao, China.* January 2023.

## **Academic Services**

Paper ACM CHI ('23)

REVIEWING IEEE PacificVis ('20, '21)

<sup>\*</sup> denotes equal contributions.

Student ACM UIST ('22)

Volunteering

## **Press Coverage**

Nov 2022 The Road to Becoming a Published Researcher, IEEE Computer Society
Aug 2018 Writing Novels on Its Own... AI Contests Human Creativity, KBS (Korean)